In hopes of saving the kids,
（リムル）
子供たちを救うために
精霊の棲家(すみか)を目指すリムルたちは
Rimuru took them in search
of the Dwelling of Spirits.
On the way, they met Ramiris,
the Queen of Spirits.
精霊女王のラミリスと出会った
Then, after earning her agreement to help,
そして 彼女の協力を得て
they set out to try to
summon superior spirits.
上位精霊を
召喚することになったのだ
So this is...
（リムル）ここが…
The deepest part of the Labyrinth,
the Dwelling of Spirits.
（ラミリス）
迷宮の最深部 精霊の棲家
Kenya, Ryota, Gale, Alice, Chloe...
（リムル）
ケンヤ リョウタ ゲイル
アリス クロエ
Let's do this!
（リムル）やるぞ！
（一同）はい！
Yeah!
Shizu-san, wherever you
are, are you watching?
（リムル）
シズさん どこかで見ているか？
I'll make sure
シズさんの思い
俺が果たしてやるから
your wish is realized.
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 23: Saved Souls
Now, listen. You'll call to
the spirits from over there.
（ラミリス）いいわね？
あそこで
精霊に対して呼びかけるのよ
（リムル）何て？
What do we say?
Anything. It can be, "Help me!"
Or even, "Let's play!"
（ラミリス）何でもいいのよ
“助けて”でも
“遊ぼう”でもね〜
If any spirits take interest and come
to you, the summon was a success.
興味を持った精霊が
やって来てくれたら成功なの
Will they actually come?
（リョウタ）来てくれるかな…
（リョウタ）うっ…
（ケンヤ）来てくれるさ！
Sure they will!
R-Right...
Sensei, they'll come, right?
（ケンヤ）
先生！　来てくれるよね？
They'll come?
（クロエ）来てくれる？
It'll be fine. In the worst case...
（リムル）大丈夫だ！
最悪の場合…
I'll tame a demon if I have to.
悪魔でも何でも 従えてやる
Uh, your face looks really evil right now.
（ラミリス）
ちょっと あんた
邪悪な顔してるわよ
So, who's going first?
（リムル）さあ 誰からいく？
Sensei...
（ゲイル）先生…
If anything happens to me, take care of them.
（ゲイル）
自分に何かあったら
あいつらを頼みます
I can't wait to see what
kind of spirit shows up!
さあ どんなのが呼ばれてくるか
楽しみだね！
じゃあ… 祈ります
Okay, I'm going to pray now.
These aren't superior spirits...
They're inferior spirits.
（リムル）
これは上位精霊じゃなくて
下位の精霊だな
If these tiny spirits
この小さな精霊たちが
are fragments cut from a great
spirit by Gale's prayer,
ゲイルの祈りが切り取った
大精霊の欠片(かけら)なら
then we just need to create a new spirit.
新しい精霊を生み出すまで…
大賢者(だいけんじゃ)
Great Sage.
Question.
（大賢者）
問(とい)…
Use Gluttony to consume
and unify the spirits?
グラトニーで捕食し
精霊の統合を行いますか？
Unify the spirits?
That's a yes, of course.
（リムル）
もちろん イエスだ
ゲイル そのまま祈ってろ
Gale, keep praying.
H-Hey!
ちょ… ちょっと！
You ate them?! How could you do that?!
食べた？
あんた なんてことすんのよ！
Keep quiet and watch. I have an idea.
黙って見ててくれ
考えはある
Go for it, Great Sage.
（リムル）
頼むぞ 大賢者
Notice.
Notice
（大賢者）
告…
ユニークスキル“変質者”により
Using the unique skill Degenerate,
Superior
Spirit
unification into a superior
spirit is complete.
上位精霊として
統合が終了いたしました
Unification
Complete
All right!
（リムル）
よし
Its attribute is earth.
（大賢者）
属性は“地”です
Attribute: Earth
Creating auxiliary artificial personality.
補助的擬似人格を作成
Creating
Auxiliary
Artificial
Personality
Success.
成功
Unify the completed artificial superior
spirit of earth with Gale Gibson?
完成した“擬似上位精霊 地”を
Earth
Artificial
Superior Spirit
ゲイル･ギブスンと統合しますか？
Gale Gibson
Unify?
（リムル）
イエス
Yes!
（リムル）
どうだ？　“解析鑑定”
How's this? Appraisal.
His rampant energy is calming down.
エネルギーの暴走が収まっている…
He's got control.
制御できた
Now, as his body matures,
これで 体が成長するに従って
徐々に能力を獲得していけるだろう
he should gradually acquire abilities.
We did it, Great Sage!
やったな！　大賢者
Heh.
I feel like I just saw Great
Sage make a smug face...
（リムル）
なんか 今 大賢者の
ドヤ顔が見えたような…
（大賢者）気のせいです
（リムル）ぐえっ
You imagined it.
おっし！　もういいぞ
よく頑張ったな
Okay, it's over. You did great.
Huh?
もう大丈夫　崩壊は止まったよ
You're okay now. The destruction's stopped.
保証してやる
I guarantee it.
S-Sensei... Thank you so much!
せ… 先生！
ありがとうございます！
Think nothing of it. It's only natural
that I'd protect my students.
気にするな
生徒を守るのは当然だからな
Hooray!
（ケンヤ）バンザ〜イ！
Congratulations!
（アリス）やったわね！
（リョウタ）おめでとう
You did it!
（クロエ）よかった…
（ランガ）ワオ〜ン！
That's great!
まだ 喜ぶのは早いぞ
It's too soon to celebrate.
Save the parties for after
you're all successful.
全員 成功してから喜ぼうぜ
Notice.
（大賢者）
告…
ユニークスキル“変質者”により
Notice
Using the unique skill Degenerate,
Superior
Spirit
unification into a superior
spirit is complete.
上位精霊として
統合が終了いたしました
Unification
Complete
Its attribute is space.
属性は“空(くう)”です
Attribute: Space
Unify the completed artificial superior
spirit of space with Alice Rondo?
（大賢者）
“擬似上位精霊 空”を作成
アリス･ロンドと統合しますか？
（リムル）
イエス
Yes.
Alice, you did great.
アリス 頑張ったな
もう大丈夫だぞ
You'll be okay now.
ありがとさん！
Well, thanks!
All right! I'm next!
う〜し！　次は俺の番だ
まだ祈ってないのに
I haven't even started praying yet...
何か来る？
Is something coming?
Hey! How are ya?
（光の精霊）いよ〜！　元気かい？
I'm just great!
おいらは元気さ
What the heck are you doing in my house?!
あんた 何しに
人の家に やって来てんのよ！
It was just a whim.
ちょっとした気まぐれだよ〜
Who is that?
（リムル）そちらさんは？
This is...
（ラミリス）こいつは…
（光の精霊）おっす！
Hiya! I'm a light spirit! Nice to meet ya!
おいら 光の精霊
はじめまして
Unlike the evil spirit that
fell to become this monster
そこの 魔物に堕(お)ちた
邪悪な妖精と違って
I'm a pure, innocent spirit of light!
純粋な光の精霊様だよ
Who are you calling evil?!
（ラミリス）誰が邪悪よ！
Kenya, it looks like you summoned
a superior spirit of light.
ケンヤ… お前
光の上位精霊を召喚したみたいだぞ
Wh-What?!
So your name's Kenya?
Okay, I'm gonna call you Ken!
ケンヤっていうのかい
じゃ ケンちゃんだな
I could just feel something shining in you, Ken!
なんか ケンちゃんに
光るものを感じたんだよ
I know, 'cause I'm light!
（光の精霊）光だけに！
（ラミリス）うっ…
面白くねえよ
That wasn't funny.
So on that note, I'm gonna save you, Ken!
てなわけで おいらが
ケンちゃんを助けてやるのだ
I'll look out for you
until you're all grown up!
ケンちゃんが成長するまでは
おいらが保護するよ
You might even become a Hero, you know!
もしかしたら ケンちゃんも勇者に
なれるかもしれないからね〜！
勇者？
A Hero?!
Ken, a Hero?
（リョウタ）ケンちゃんが勇者！
（ゲイル）おお〜
Wow...
（ケンヤ）うえ〜
（リムル）それはまた…
Well, that would be something...
（リムル）あっ！
（ラミリス）宿った
It inhabited you...
Huh?
（ケンヤ）え…
（リムル）そんな あっさりと
That easily?
Sensei...
（ケンヤ）先生…
Huh?
Oh, yeah! It's fine! All according to plan!
ああ 大丈夫　計画どおりだ
ハハハハッ よかったな！
Good for you!
Er, uh...
あっ えっと…
Yeah!
Notice.
（大賢者）
告　属性は“水”と“風”
Notice
Its attributes are water and wind.
Attributes
Water
Wind
Creation of artificial superior
spirit of water and wind successful.
“擬似上位精霊 水風(すいふう)”を作成
Artificial
Superior
Spirit
成功しました
Success
Unify it with Ryota Sekiguchi?
リョウタ･セキグチと
統合しますか？
Yes.
（リムル）
イエ〜ス♪
Just one left.
あと１人…
Sensei, um... Sensei...
（小声で）先生 あのね　先生…
（クロエ）
あのね 先生… あのね…
Um, Sensei... um...
だ〜い好き
I love you!
俺も好きだよ
Well, I like you, too.
I wish you'd waited another eight...
no, ten years to say that.
（リムル）
せめて あと８年…
いや 10年ぐらいたってから
言ってほしかった
Hell, I wish I'd heard
that while I was alive!
ていうか 生前に言ってほしかった
Go on and pray.
さっ 祈って
Okay.
（ラミリス）なに？
What's that?
That pressure...
It felt like the sky fell down.
（リムル）
今の 天が落ちてきたような
プレッシャーは…
（リムル）
ん？　精霊… ではない？
That's... not a spirit?
Answer.
（大賢者）
解(かい)…
It is a spiritual body equivalent
to a superior spirit.
上位精霊と同様の
スピリチュアル･ボディーです
Abnormal level of energy detected.
異常なまでのエネルギーを検知
Its threshold is immeasurable.
上限は 測定不能です
What the...
一体…
Hold it! No way, no how!
待て！　させないよ
I'm not letting you have your way!
あんたの好きにはさせない！
Hey, what the heck are you—
おい 突然 何を…
Quiet! That thing's dangerous!
Can't you see that?!
（ラミリス）
うるさい！　そいつはヤバいんだよ
見て分からないの？
分かるわけないだろ！
何がヤバいんだ？
How the hell would I know?!
What's so dangerous?
We'll talk later!
話は あと… うわっ！
It inhabited her!
宿っちゃった
もう手遅れだ…
Darn it! It's too late!
Well, I'm done!
Don't blame me for whatever happens!
やめやめ！
アタシは知らないからね？
Appraisal.
（リムル）
“解析鑑定”
That immense energy has
completely disappeared.
膨大だったエネルギーが
きれいさっぱりと消え失(う)せてる
She seems... stable.
状態は… 安定化してる
Looks like there's no problem...
何も問題ないような…
But what in the world...
だが 一体…
So just what was that?
さっきのは何だったんだ？
No idea! I don't know the details!
（ラミリス）
分っかんないわよ！
詳しくは分からない
But I'm pretty sure that
one was born in the future.
でもね あれは 多分
未来で生まれたのよ
Huh?
It's something resembling a spirit,
except it came from the future!
未来からやって来た
精霊に似た何か！
It's almost impossible to believe,
とても信じられないけど
but by inhabiting her, it laid the
foundation for its own rebirth?
その子に宿ったことで
自分を生み出す土壌を作った？
What are you talking about?
何 言ってんだ？
I seriously don't know!
（ラミリス）
ああ〜 ホントに分からない！
But that thing had enormous power!
でも あれは大きな力を持ってた
I'm pretty sure it'll be big trouble
if that thing is born in the future!
未来で あれが生まれたら
大変なことになる気がする！
もしかして あれは
時の大精霊の加護を受けて…
Maybe it had the divine protection
of the Great Spirit of Time...
I'm completely lost!
（リムル）
さっぱり分からん！
But it's all good. As long as Chloe's
okay, that's all that matters.
結果オーライ
クロエが無事なら それでいい
No one knows what'll happen in the
future, so it means nothing right now!
確定もしてない未来のことなんて
今は どうでもいいの！
Good for you, Chloe.
It went just as I planned.
（リムル）
よかったな クロエ
計画どおりだ
You're out of danger now, too.
お前も無事に 危険を回避したぞ
Was that really just as you planned it?
本当に計画どおりなの？
Y-Yeah! Of course!
あ… ああ　もちろんだとも
（ランガ）ワオ〜ン！
（２人）うわ…
I mean, not that it matters.
（ラミリス）まっ いいけどね
Now that it's inhabited her,
it's out of my control.
その子に宿った時点で
既に アタシの手に負えないし
What's the problem?
Everyone was successful.
いいじゃないか
全員 成功したんだからさ
Thanks! These kids are saved, thanks to you!
ありがとな！
お前のおかげで
子供たちも助かったよ
Thank you!
（クロエ）ありがとう
（ラミリス）う…
Thank you!
（４人）ありがとうございました！
（ランガ）感謝する！
I'm grateful!
C-Cut that out already!
そ… そんなの いいってば〜！
And this is a Demon Lord?
What has the world come to?
（リムル）
これが魔王だなんて
ホント 世の中は
どうなっているのやら
I did it, Shizu-san.
（リムル）
やったよ シズさん
They'll be okay now.
もう… 大丈夫だ
It was a happy ending!
（リムル）
これで めでたし めでたし…
Or so I thought, but after that...
と思ったが このあと
I had to give Ramiris a replacement
for the golem I destroyed...
ラミリスに 俺が消滅させた
ゴーレムの代わりを用意したり
Then I had to summon a demon and
make it possess that golem...
そのゴーレムに悪魔を召喚して
憑依(ひょうい)させたりして
And there was one last struggle.
もうひと悶着(もんちゃく)あった
But hey, that's a different story.
まあ それは別の話である
（ユウキ）
本当に
ありがとうございました
I truly thank you.
Nah, no worries, no worries!
（リムル）
いやいや
いいってことよ いいってことよ
The kids will be fine now.
子供たちは もう大丈夫だ
Guess they'll be able to
live normal lives, huh?
これで 普通の生活を送れるよな
Yes.
It's unlikely the nations that abandoned
them will ever try to take them back.
一度捨てた子を 各国が再び
さらうことはないでしょうし
That would violate international law, anyway.
それは国際法に抵触しますし
我々 自由組合を
敵に回すことにもなりますから
They'd be making enemies of the
Free Union if they did that.
Are you going to give the kids IDs
and make them members of the Union?
（リムル）
子供たちにも身分証を発行して
組合員にするのか？
Well, if that's what they want,
that might be a very good idea.
そうですね
あの子たちが それを望むなら
それもいいかもしれないですね
But for the time being, I'd like to
let them study at the Freedom Academy
しばらくは 自由学園で
伸び伸びと勉強させて
and give them the chance
to choose their future.
未来を選べるようにしたいと
思います
Okay. I'm counting on you.
（リムル）ああ 頼むよ
You needn't worry.
ご心配なく
By the way, you still won't tell
me how you resolved all this?
ところで…
やっぱり教えてくれないんですか？
どうやって解決したのか
（リムル）フフフ… それは秘密だ
That's a secret.
There are some things you don't need to know.
知らなくてもいいこともあるよ
It's no substitute for telling you,
教えない代わり…
というわけでもないが
これで勘弁してほしい…
but I hope you'll be content with this...
Understood! Thank you, Master!
（ユウキ）
分かりました！
ありがとうございます 師匠〜！
Hey, wait up!
（ケンヤ）待てよ！
So much has happened...
（リムル）
本当に… いろいろあったな
But now this case is closed.
でも これで 一件落着
All of our problems have been solved.
問題は全て解決だ
Shizu-san, this is for the best, right?
シズさん これでいいんだよな
Thank you, Slime-san.
（シズ）
ありがとう スライムさん
What a horrible blunder.
（男）一生の不覚
You finally summoned me,
せっかく呼んでいただけたのに
自分の眷属(けんぞく)に先を越されるとは…
and my own family got ahead of me.
Next time, without a doubt...
次こそ… 次こそは必ずや
I know you will lead me to
the truth of this world.
あなた様なら 私を
世界の真理へと導いてくれるはず
クッフフ…
Sensei... Sensei, don't go...
（クロエ）先生…
先生 行っちゃやだ
Chlo-chi... Don't try to keep Sensei here.
クロっち
先生を引き止めるのは ダメだよ
そうよ！　さっさと行きなさいよ
Yeah! Just get going already!
でも…
But...
フウ…
頼むぞ
Take care of them.
I will. You can count on me.
ええ お任せください
先生！
Sensei!
（ケンヤ）
ま… まったく クロエは泣き虫だな
Jeez, Chloe, you're such a crybaby.
Stop crying!
泣くなよ！
ケンちゃんだって…
You're crying, too, Ken-chan...
目から汗が出ただけだ！
I'm not! My eyes are just sweating!
（クロエ）先生… 先生…
Sensei... Sensei...
Chloe.
クロエ
There, there, Chloe.
よしよし クロエ
これをやるから 元気出せよ！
I'll give you this, so cheer up, okay?
I wanted that, too!
私も欲しかったのに！
エヘヘ 私が もらったの
But I got it.
いいな いいな！
Lucky!
No fair! No fair!
ずるい ずるい！
Oh, right. I have gifts for you guys, too.
（リムル）
そうだ
アリスたちにもプレゼントがある
Ken-chan, you look awesome!
ケンちゃん かっこいい！
リョウタだって
So do you!
These are fantastic!
すばらしいですね
I-It's so cute!
（アリス）か… かわいい！
There's a really handy girl
named Shuna in my country.
国に シュナって
手先の器用な子がいてな
I had her make those and send them.
作って送ってもらったんだ
（ケンヤ）先生！
（クロエ）ありがとう
Sensei...
Thank you!
Now, listen. Be sure you study hard.
（リムル）
いいか？　しっかり勉強しろよ
Saying goodbye is sad, but it's
not as if we'll never meet again.
別れは つらいが
二度と会えなくなるわけじゃない
（５人）うっ…
I'll bring Ranga and come visit you.
（リムル）
ランガも連れて遊びに来るから
Be sure to keep up with your studies,
even after we leave!
（ランガ）
我らがいなくても
しっかり勉強するのだぞ！
Y-You'd better come visit us!
か… 必ず遊びに来てくれよ
Wh-When I graduate, I might
just come visit you, too!
そそそ… 卒業したら
こっちから
行ってあげてもいいんだからね！
Sure. I'll be waiting.
ああ 待ってる
I'll have the entire city
of Rimuru welcome you.
中央都市リムルの町を挙げて
大歓迎だ！
（ケンヤ）先生〜！
（リョウタ）またね！
Sensei!
See you again!
Take care!
Goodbye!
（ゲイル）さようなら！
（アリス）気をつけて〜！
Be well!
元気でな〜！
See you again.
またね
Master, why did you give
her your treasured mask?
（ランガ）主(あるじ)よ
なぜ 大切な仮面を渡したのです？
ん？　ああ… なんでだろうな
Yeah, I wonder why, too...
I'm not sure either,
俺にも分からない
but for some reason, giving it to Chloe
felt like the natural thing to do.
だけど なぜか クロエにあげるのが
自然なことだと思ったんだ
Something told me that was best.
それが いちばんだって
I see.
（ランガ）なるほど
I bet Shizu-san would be happier
with Chloe having it than me.
（リムル）
シズさんだって 俺より
クロエに持っててもらったほうが
うれしいんじゃないか？
She'll take good care of it.
彼女なら大切にしてくれるだろうし
She might even follow in Shizu-san's
footsteps to become a champion...
シズさんの後を継いで 英雄に…
Heck, she might even become a Hero!
もしかしたら
勇者にだってなるかもしれないぞ！
（ランガ）まさか
Surely not!
Ranga!
（リムル）ランガ
（ランガ）はっ 我が主！
Yes, Master!
Let's go back to our town... to our home!
俺たちの町に… 家に帰ろう
みんなが待ってる
Everyone's waiting!
ワオ〜ン！
The man who thought he was living
a perfectly ordinary life
（リムル）
なんということもない
普通の人生を歩むはずだった男は
was stabbed by a random attacker and died,
通り魔に刺されて死亡し
異世界に転生を果たした
and was reincarnated in another world.
He took in the Storm Dragon Veldora
暴風竜ヴェルドラ
as well as the will and
body of a certain girl,
そして
１人の女性の思いと姿を受け継ぎ
overcame many crises,
幾度もの危機を乗り越え
さまざまな種族の魔物をまとめて
brought together many races of monsters,
built a nation, and saved
a group of children.
国を作り 子供たちを救った
His name is Rimuru Tempest,
その名は
リムル＝テンペスト
and he is but a slime.
１匹のスライムである
Next time, "Extra: Black and a Mask."
（大賢者）
次回「外伝:黒と仮面」
Extra: Black and a Mask